<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sockets on Rayyan Shaik</title>
    <link>http:rayyanshaik.com/tags/sockets/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sockets on Rayyan Shaik</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http:rayyanshaik.com/tags/sockets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Simple Dungeon Game</title>
      <link>http:rayyanshaik.com/blog/simple-dungeon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http:rayyanshaik.com/blog/simple-dungeon/</guid>
      <description>Description A showcase-esque project designed to demonstrate an improved understanding of sockets and client/network relationships. This was created in pure python with no game engines (such as Unity), everything from buttons, to servers, to the physics was created from scratch. This is not a complete game, but includes complete portions of one - a main menu screen, working (not much playable content) game, and a level editor. This project features complex gui components created from scratch, such as buttons and text boxes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agar.io Clone</title>
      <link>http:rayyanshaik.com/blog/agario/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http:rayyanshaik.com/blog/agario/</guid>
      <description>Description A complete, scalable clone of the popular web game, agar.io. This project was created purely in python, and utilizes the pygame (GUI) and sockets (web connection) libraries. There are 2 main files used to run code. The first is client.py, which runs the game itself. The second is server.py, which can be run on any network and can open a customizable &amp;ldquo;agar.io&amp;rdquo; server on any port. This game is playable online, and through local networks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
