<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rayyan Shaik</title>
    <link>https://rayyanshaik.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Rayyan Shaik</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rayyanshaik.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://rayyanshaik.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayyanshaik.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I am Rayyan Shaik, a 16 year old Junior at Windermere Preparatory School. Programming is something I&amp;rsquo;m very passionate about, and a skill that I had started learning during my years in middle school. Since then, I have completed AP Computer Science (score of 5 on AP Exam), a cybersecurity summer course at Embry Riddle (Through a National Security Agency scholarship), and I am also currently enrolled in IB Computer Science (Higher Level).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2048 AI</title>
      <link>https://rayyanshaik.com/timeline/2048ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayyanshaik.com/timeline/2048ai/</guid>
      <description>Description 2048 is a popular web game, in which the player shifts numbered tiles across a 4x4 grid to create the number 2048. This project showcases my python clone of the game itself, and AI that can beat it quite effectively, using Monte Carlo simulations.
Github Repository The Github repository can be found here
What were my goals with this project?  Implementation of Monte Carlo simulations A clean and efficient clone of the game 2048.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OsuBot</title>
      <link>https://rayyanshaik.com/timeline/osubot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayyanshaik.com/timeline/osubot/</guid>
      <description>Description This is a discord bot designed to provide easily accessible statistics for the game osu! - a rhythm game with a wide player base. This bot can be used on the messaging &amp;amp; gaming platform &amp;ldquo;discord&amp;rdquo;.
The bot utilizes a few APIs and intuitive web scraping to easily find and calculate generalized and specific statsitics for osu! players. There are several osu! discord bots provide these statistics, however, what makes this bot unique are some of its original commands - notably the o.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-driving Car AI</title>
      <link>https://rayyanshaik.com/timeline/carai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayyanshaik.com/timeline/carai/</guid>
      <description>Description This project is a simple racing game that implements a neural network to have agents automatically race around the track. This project itself is split up into 3 parts: the map builder, gui/game, and deep neural network.
Github Repository The Github repository can be found here
What were my goals with this project?  Implementation and design of neural networks Imeplementation and design of a genetic algorithm Object oriented design Track builder script (to create custom-tailored tracks for the car agents)  Project Images  Training process   Track Builder    Dependencies   Pygame Numpy Shapely  Car-Racing-NN README.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathematical Expression Evaluator</title>
      <link>https://rayyanshaik.com/timeline/calculator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayyanshaik.com/timeline/calculator/</guid>
      <description>Description This repository features 2 programs that can solve mathematical expressions. Both projects were planned and thought out before writing, and my partner, Andrew Diab, and I each wrote one implementation. The first one, under the subdirectory /Dijkstra was completed by Andrew Diab - this implements the Shunting-Yard Algorithm by Edsger Dijkstra, and the simpleSolve() method created by myself. I created the second implementation found under the subdirectory Recursive. This program contains a class which can solve unordered mathematical expressions folling PEMDAS (no brackets or parentheses) under the method simpleSolve().</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Velociraptor Bot</title>
      <link>https://rayyanshaik.com/timeline/velociraptorbot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayyanshaik.com/timeline/velociraptorbot/</guid>
      <description>Description A multi-purpose discord bot to be used on a private server with my friends. This bot provides basic security for our server with an easily customizable verification system. Important e-learnig and virtual learning commands that can reply with my school&amp;rsquo;s schedule and per class zoom links. The bot can also join voice channels and play different sound effects stored as .mp3 files.
Github Repository The Github repository can be found here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Dungeon Game</title>
      <link>https://rayyanshaik.com/timeline/simple-dungeon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayyanshaik.com/timeline/simple-dungeon/</guid>
      <description>Description A showcase-esque project designed to demonstrate an improved understanding of sockets and client/network relationships. This was created in pure python with no game engines (such as Unity), everything from buttons, to servers, to the physics was created from scratch. This is not a complete game, but includes complete portions of one - a main menu screen, working (not much playable content) game, and a level editor. This project features complex gui components created from scratch, such as buttons and text boxes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agar.io Clone</title>
      <link>https://rayyanshaik.com/timeline/agario/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayyanshaik.com/timeline/agario/</guid>
      <description>Description A complete, scalable clone of the popular web game, agar.io. This project was created purely in python, and utilizes the pygame (GUI) and sockets (web connection) libraries. There are 2 main files used to run code. The first is client.py, which runs the game itself. The second is server.py, which can be run on any network and can open a customizable &amp;ldquo;agar.io&amp;rdquo; server on any port. This game is playable online, and through local networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Rockets</title>
      <link>https://rayyanshaik.com/timeline/smart-rockets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayyanshaik.com/timeline/smart-rockets/</guid>
      <description>Description This program is a demonstration of a genetic algorithm, with the use of &amp;ldquo;rockets&amp;rdquo; drawn as rectangles. Each &amp;ldquo;rocket&amp;rdquo; has its own dna telling them random directions to accelerate towards. Rockets effectively gain a higher (better) fitness the closer they are to the goal (green circle) and lose fitness (worse) if they try and go out of bounds or hit a boundary. In the scope of the genetic algorithm, these fitness scores are used to create the next &amp;ldquo;generation&amp;rdquo; of rocket which favors (not absolute) to combine dna of the top performing rockets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agent-Maze Environment</title>
      <link>https://rayyanshaik.com/timeline/agent-maze/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rayyanshaik.com/timeline/agent-maze/</guid>
      <description>Description A project developed by WPS Lakerbotics Programming Team, designed as a testing environment for pathfinding &amp;ldquo;agent&amp;rdquo; algorithms.
Github Repository The Github repository can be found here
What were my goals with this project?  Practice advanced manipulation of 2d arrays Practice GUI efficiency Minimalist and attractive graphics Object-Oriented approach Object reading and writing with pickle library  Project Images       Dependencies  Pygame Numpy Pickle  Agent-Maze-Environment README.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
